OJO TOKUNBO KAYODE

11, Association Avenue, Shangisha, Magodo. Lagos state.

Phone: +234 8149479163

E-mail: ojo_tokunbo2002@yahoo.com

Summary

Full stack engineer.

Frontend development experience using AngularJS and Vuejs

Backend development with PHP (codeigniter, laravel, yii2), Node (express), Java

(Springboot)

Experience leading small to medium sized teams.

Professional Skills

Backend: PHP, Java (springboot), Nodejs

Frontend: JQuery, AngularJS, Vuejs

Others: Meteorjs

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Version Control: Git

Platforms: windows, Linux

Devops: Heroku, Azure, Docker, DigitalOcean

OTHERS

Knowledge and experience of software development using Object Oriented Approach.

Experience Developing in MVC and HMVC software architectural patterns.

Good understanding of software development life cycle.

Experience developing RESTful APIs.

Practical knowledge of the SOLID principle of software design.

Experience in unit and integration testing.

Experience developing apps using the microservice architecture with Eureka

Professional Experience

C2G Consulting: Apr 2019 - Present

259, Etim Iyang crescent, Victoria Island. Lagos.

Position: Solution Architect

Roles:

- Core Software development.
- Recommending technical specifications for software projects.
- Design and development of software processes.

Bincom ICT: July 2017 - Feb 2019 5, Anthony Ajayi Street, Yaba. Lagos.

Position: Senior Associate

Roles:

- Core Software development
- Design and implementation of processes.
- Managing junior developers
- Worked with clients to understand business requirements and translate to software specification.
- Provided high-level support both remotely and onsite
- Ensuring the quality of code and best practices
- Software maintenance including feature upgrades
- Ensuring software and process Documentation

EBIS (Enterprise Business Information System): June, 2016 - October, 2017

Suite 23, Canan plaza, Marwa Estate, Lekki Estate

Position: Software Developer

Roles:

- Software development
- Provide support to clients.

Skye Bank Plc: June 2014- January 2015

Assbifi Rd, Ikeja, Lagos. Position: I.T Support

Roles:

- Provide high-end support to the different branches
- Maintenance of the infrastructures.

Projects

Airtelcoop

Development of Financial assets management solution and e-portal for the Airtel cooperative society, one of the biggest such cooperatives in Nigeria. These solution was responsible for recording, processing and managing members' savings, determining loan eligibility status of members, disbursing of loans, recording and tracking of payments, disbursing dividends

- Recording, processing and managing members' savings
- determining loan eligibility status of members based on the statutory labor laws
- Managing the process of loan application end to end
- Disbursing of loans
- Tracking paybacks and Debt management.
- Disbursing dividends
- Balancing of accounts.

Devops: AWS

Languages: Laravel, Angular

Marivat

Automated tax collection solution developed for Federal Inland revenue Service (FIRS). This project included

- Direct integration with the ERP of the concessionaires to get transactions out of their system.
- Calculate the Vatable amount from these transactions, excluding VAT exempt/ zero rated supplies and services
- Integration with a payment gateway, in this case (Remita) to set up a direct debit mandate for deducting the vat payable.
- Report and tracking of payment failures and downtime.

Devops: Azure, Azure container instances, Docker

Languages: meteoris, nodejs

Social Lender

A lending platform that determines eligibility based on social reputation score as a leverage for disbursing loans to individuals. This leveraged on the strength of the

individual's social network and certain key identifiers which is passed through an AI algorithm to determine the social reputation score.

Devops: DigitalOcean, AWS **Languages:** meteorjs, nodejs

Links

Github: https://github.com/theekhay

Stackoverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/8439622/ojo-tokunbo

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tokunbo-ojo-35419a75

Educational Background

Federal University of Technology, Akure (FUTA) 2010 - 2015

B.TECH Computer Science

Federal Government College, Ijanikin. Lagos 2003 - 2009

Senior School Certificate Examination (WAEC)

Interests and Activities

Programming, Movies, physics

References available on request.